scene.ca 2013-05-16

# SCENE - Privacy Policy

### Privacy Policy

#### We protect your privacy

SCENE® is a loyalty program that is operated by Scene Limited Partnership (" **Scene LP** "). Cineplex Entertainment LP (" **Cineplex** ") and The Bank of Nova Scotia (" **Scotiabank** ") are the limited partners and originating sponsors (which, including their subsidiaries, affiliates and joint ventures, are described below as the " **Sponsors** " hereinafter referred to as " **us** ", " **we** " or " **our** ") of Scene LP and the SCENE loyalty program (" **SCENE** " or " **Program** "). All of your dealings with Scene LP, the Program and the scene.ca website are governed by this Privacy Policy (" **Policy** ").

A list of SCENE Sponsors and reward partners can be found at scene.ca and may be updated from time to time as Sponsors and reward partners join or leave the Program. This Policy applies to the originating sponsors and any new sponsors that join SCENE in the future. 

SCENE is committed to protecting your right to privacy. We treat your personal information with the utmost of respect and operate in strict accordance with all privacy legislation. Please take the time to familiarize yourself with this Policy as it outlines how we collect, use, disclose and protect your personal information. We also recommend that you periodically review this Policy as it may be altered or updated from time to time. 

#### What is personal information?

" **Personal information** " is information about an identifiable individual member of the SCENE loyalty program (" **Member** "). This may include, without limitation, your name, mailing address, e-mail address, age, member number and password and certain demographic information. 

#### Collecting, using and disclosing your personal information

Your personal information will not be collected, used or disclosed without your consent. Scene LP only collects the information that we need to provide services to you and to administer SCENE. We collect your personal information through: 

  * Your enrollment in SCENE;
  * Online and electronic activity with Scene LP;
  * Telephone, paper and online surveys and contests; and,
  * Your use of your SCENE membership card and SCENE® _ScotiaCard_ MD and SCENE VISA* card issued by Scotiabank.

The personal information we collect includes your name, mailing address, home telephone number and e-mail address. We ask for your birth date to verify eligibility for SCENE and to facilitate the automatic connection and/or enrollment of your Scene membership account to your Scene _ScotiaCard_ and/or Scene Visa card. We also ask you to choose a password to verify your identity, and a unique question related to your password. We may also ask for your cell number and secure messaging service number, but providing this information is optional. We will disclose your name, email address, postal code, birth date and home telephone number to Scotiabank for the purpose of connecting your Scene membership account with your Scene _ScotiaCard_ and/or Scene Visa card. 

We may collect additional information from you to create a member profile including marital status, number of people in household, household income, gender, education, home language, movie-going preferences and information that identifies you as an existing Scotiabank customer, if applicable. Providing this information is optional. We do not collect the personal information of individuals under 14 years of age and only collect a limited amount of personal information from Members who are under the age of majority in the province in which they reside. For further details on this matter please see the SCENE Terms and Conditions available at [www.scene.ca](https://www.scene.ca/). 

We collect, use and disclose your personal information for the following purposes:

  * To set up and administer SCENE including ongoing management of SCENE accounts, and to accurately record points and up-to-date point balances;
  * To process SCENE redemptions and issue rewards;
  * To allow you to participate in promotions and contests;
  * To communicate with you and to deliver a SCENE e-newsletter;
  * To understand your needs and preferences, and to provide you with products and services that meet your needs;
  * To recommend the products and services of SCENE, our Sponsors and reward partners or the products and services of third parties we select that may be of interest to you;
  * To provide you with special offers and rewards from SCENE, our Sponsors and reward partners;
  * To facilitate or enable any corporate or commercial transaction involving Scene LP.

We do not provide directly all the services related to your relationship with us. We may use third party service providers to process or handle personal information on our behalf. A third party service provider is someone other than Scotiabank, Cineplex and any of their respective subsidiaries or affiliates. Some of our third party service providers may be located outside of Canada and subject to foreign legislation. As a result, your personal information may be accessible to regulatory authorities in accordance with the law of these jurisdictions. When personal information is provided to our service providers, we require them to protect the information in a manner that is consistent with this Policy.

You agree that we may use, disclose to and collect from credit bureaus or financial service industry databases, credit and other information about you in order to offer you pre-approved credit products . You may withdraw your consent at any time by giving us reasonable notice. 

#### SCENE _ScotiaCard_ s from Scotiabank

Eligible SCENE Members will be entitled to apply for the SCENE __ScotiaCard__ banking card or SCENE™ VISA* credit card issued by Scotiabank.

The SCENE __ScotiaCard__ banking card and SCENE VISA credit card are subject to separate Terms and Conditions, and a separate application must be completed to enroll for these cards. These documents can be found on the [www.scene.ca](https://www.scene.ca/) website. The SCENE __ScotiaCard__ banking card and SCENE VISA credit card are subject to the Scotiabank Group Privacy Agreement, which is available on the Scotiabank website at [www.scotiabank.com](https://www.scotiabank.com/). 

#### Consent

By providing us with your personal information, we assume that you consent to our collecting, using and disclosing this information for the purposes described in this Policy.

We may ask you for contact information such as your telephone or fax number, and keep and use this information as well as disclose it to SCENE Sponsors and rewards partners so that we or our third party suppliers may contact you directly through these channels for the purpose of marketing including telemarketing. For greater clarity, " **we** " includes subsidiaries, affiliates and joint ventures. This consent will also apply to SCENE Sponsors, reward partners and any other companies that form a part of or join SCENE in the future. Your consent to this is not a condition of doing business with us and you may withdraw it at any time by following the instructions below . You may contact us regarding any telemarketing issues by calling us toll free at 1-866-586-2805 or by email at [help@scene.ca](mailto:help@scene.ca).

We will not collect, use or disclose your personal information without your consent unless it is necessary to do so by law, for example in response to a court order or subpoena, to detect and prevent fraud or other criminal activity, or to comply with our legal and regulatory requirements.

We will obtain your consent before using or disclosing personal information for a purpose that has not been specified in this Policy, unless the new purpose is required by law. 

#### Withdrawing consent

Subject to legal, regulatory and contractual requirements, you may withdraw your consent to our collection, use or disclosure of your personal information at any time by giving us reasonable notice. Depending on the circumstances, however, withdrawal of your consent may impact on our ability to provide you or to continue to provide you with some of the privileges and opportunities of SCENE membership.

You cannot refuse our collection, use and disclosure of information required by third party service providers essential for the administration and management of the Program.

You can tell us at any time to stop using information about you to promote our products and services or the products and services of third parties we select. If you wish to withdraw consent as outlined in this Policy, you may do so at any time by following these instructions: [log into www.scene.ca](https://www.scene.ca/login.aspx), click on " **My Account** ", click on " **Edit Profile** ", scroll down to the section " **Other Information** " and click on " **edit** " in the upper right hand corner of that section. You may then change the " **Subscribe** " flag to " **Unsubscribe** " for SCENE communications and specific partner offers.

We will act on your instructions as quickly as possible but there may be certain uses of your information that we may not be able to stop immediately. 

#### Security, retention and destruction of personal information

We do our utmost to protect and safeguard your personal information using physical, electronic and procedural measures appropriate to the sensitivity of the information, including safeguards to protect your information against loss and theft, as well as unauthorized access, disclosure, copying, use, or modification.

We retain personal information in accordance with this Policy, legislative requirements and documented guidelines and procedures established by Scene LP. Our employees may require access to your personal information in order to set up and manage the Program. Employees are required, as a condition of employment, to conform to all privacy policies and procedures.

We will only keep your personal information for as long as it is required to fulfill the purposes for which it was collected. We may retain your information for a certain amount of time after you cease to be a Member, but only for so long as it is required for us to have the necessary information to respond to any issue that may arise at a later date. 

#### Cookies

Cookies may be used by our web server to automatically recognize you as a registered visitor, where you have indicated your preference to be automatically logged in.

You can disable cookies using your Internet browser’s settings. Please consult your browser’s help function for information on how to disable cookies. Note that if you disable cookies, certain features of our website will not function properly. We use pixels, or transparent GIF files, to help manage online advertising. These GIF files are provided by our ad management partner, DoubleClick. These files enable DoubleClick to recognize a unique cookie on your Web browser, which in turn enables us to learn which advertisements bring users to our website.

The cookie was placed by us, or by another advertiser who works with DoubleClick. With both cookies and Spotlight technology, the information that we collect and share is anonymous and not personally identifiable. It does not contain your name, address, telephone number, or email address. For more information about DoubleClick, including information about how to opt out of these technologies, go to [ <http://www.doubleclick.net/us/corporate/privacy> ]. 

#### External links

The [www.scene.ca](https://www.scene.ca/) website may contain links or references to other websites to which this Policy does not apply. For example, when you click a link to take advantage of other third party services, our website may indicate that you are leaving [www.scene.ca](https://www.scene.ca/) and using a third-party website for those purposes. Please be advised that these sites are not owned or controlled by Scene LP. When providing personal information on other websites not controlled or owned by Scene LP we encourage you to read the privacy policy of those sites. 

#### Changes to this Privacy Policy

This Policy may be amended from time to time to ensure the protection of your personal information and compliance with privacy legislation. If we make any substantial changes, we will notify you by posting a notice and the revised Policy on the [www.scene.ca](https://www.scene.ca/) website. 

#### How to reach us

If you have a general question or you have a concern regarding this Policy or would like to access or update your personal or account information, please contact us by calling toll-free at 1 866-586-2805 or by email at [help@scene.ca](mailto:help@scene.ca). Please indicate clearly the information that you wish us to review or have changed. We will endeavour to reply to your request as soon as reasonably possible. If you have a sensory disability, please let us know and we will work to accommodate your needs. 

_SCENE is a registered trademark of SCENE IP LP._  
_Cineplex_ is a registered trademark and _Escape with Us_ TM is a trademark of Cineplex Entertainment LP, used under license.  
_Scotiabank_ and _ScotiaCard_ are registered trademarks of The Bank of Nova Scotia, used under license.  
* Visa Int./Lic. user The Bank of Nova Scotia.
